<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>People on LPS Qubit Collaboratory</title>
    <link>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in People on LPS Qubit Collaboratory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/2020-august-gov-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/2020-august-gov-positions/</guid>
      <description>Please apply here or inquire about open positions at the LPS Qubit Collaboratory.
Responsibilities NSA is home to one of the largest and most established in-house research organizations within the U.S. Intelligence Community (IC), employing scientists with world-class skills in fields such as mathematics, physics, computer science, engineering, and cybersecurity. We collaborate with leading industries, universities, and national laboratories to advance core competencies, leverage work in overlapping disciplines, and solve some of the most challenging national security problems thought to be intractable by adversaries and commercial industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/lqc-workforce-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/lqc-workforce-programs/</guid>
      <description>Building a &amp;ldquo;quantum-smart&amp;rdquo; workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LQC Open Positions</title>
      <link>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/lqc-open-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/lqc-open-positions/</guid>
      <description>The Laboratory for Physical Sciences, located at the University of Maryland-College Park, is a unique organization where university, industry, and federal government scientists collaborate on research in advanced computer, sensing, and networking technologies. Working at LPS can take the form of government, UMD, and industry positions at multiple skill levels. See below for current opportunities.
Inquire about open positions at the LPS Qubit Collaboratory. LPS Lead Researcher Positions (Government) Detailed job descriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People and Partners</title>
      <link>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/lqc-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lps.thomaswong.net/people/lqc-people/</guid>
      <description>Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) Research Leads  Bob Butera, PhD Frank Gaitan, PhD Bruce Kane, PhD Ari Mizel, PhD Kevin Osborn, PhD Ben Palmer, PhD Chris Richardson, PhD, Deputy Director Charles Tahan, PhD, Director  Researchers  Coming soon  Graduate Students  Coming soon  Staff  Kim Pinckney-Lewis, PhD, Outreach Lead   LQC Visitors Faculty  Hugh Churchill, PhD, University of Arkansas, Summer 2021 Tom Wong, PhD, Creighton University, Summer 2021 - January 2022  Students  Chris McNally, MIT, Summer 2021   Partners LPS was founded on the campus of the University of Maryland in 1957.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
