<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LPS Qubit Collaboratory</title>
    <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LPS Qubit Collaboratory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recent Dissertation Defense: Measuring and Trapping Quasiparticles in Superconducting Coplanar Waveguide Resonators</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/alexander-dissertation-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/alexander-dissertation-defense/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Dr. Ashish Alexander who successfully defended his Ph.D. doctoral thesis in Electrical Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gapped Frustration-Free Local Spin Chains</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/mizel-local-spin-chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/mizel-local-spin-chains/</guid>
      <description>The Mizel group has held a long-standing interest in the adiabatic quantum computation paradigm and in the technical issues surrounding temperature. Recently, the group published a paper in Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter proposing a model system [2] that performs a trivial computation — a series of approximate identity gates applied to a single quantum bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synopsis of the Workshop on Gaps in Postsecondary Quantum Education and Training</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/synopsis-of-the-workshop-on-gaps-in-postsecondary-quantum-education-and-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/synopsis-of-the-workshop-on-gaps-in-postsecondary-quantum-education-and-training/</guid>
      <description>On October 12, 2021, the Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) Qubit Collaboratory (LQC) hosted a free virtual, public Workshop on Gaps in Postsecondary Quantum Education and Training. There were over a hundred registrants, speakers, and panelists including representatives from academia, industry, and government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPS/LQC Open House</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/open-house/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for University of Maryland students interested in Research Assistantships at The Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Quantum Recruitment in Government</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/quantum-recruitment-in-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/quantum-recruitment-in-government/</guid>
      <description>The Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) hosted a workshop on Quantum Recruitment in Government with approximately forty participants, representing a variety of government agencies, federally funded research and development centers, and a university affiliated research center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of Quantum Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/summer-of-quantum-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/summer-of-quantum-recap/</guid>
      <description>The Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) Qubit Collaboratory (LQC) hosted its inaugural, free Summer of Quantum Workshop July 12 – 23, 2021. Fifty-four (54) national and international participants received an introduction to quantum computing from algorithms to physical implementations, including quantum tutorials and interactive, hands-on projects led by leading quantum scientists from LPS and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSA launches LPS Qubit Collaboratory</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/nsa-launches-lps-qubit-collaboratory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/nsa-launches-lps-qubit-collaboratory/</guid>
      <description>Today the National Security Agency’s Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) launched the LPS Qubit Collaboratory (LQC), a Quantum Information Science research center in support of the U.S. National Quantum Initiative. The LQC offers a mechanism for collaborative research between LPS and academia, industry, FFRDCs, and Government Laboratories. The Army Research Office, in partnership with LPS, has announced a Broad Agency Announcement (BAA) for the LPS Qubit Collaboratory that introduces the initial research areas of the LQC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPS announces first-ever qubit collaboratory</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/lps-announces-first-ever-qubit-collaboratory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/news/lps-announces-first-ever-qubit-collaboratory/</guid>
      <description>The quantum world hosts a rich variety of physics that could enable functionality far beyond what traditional technologies can achieve. By probing and manipulating phenomena that occur at the single particle scale, the emerging field of quantum information science (QIS) aims to create new forms of computing, sensing, and communications that could revolutionize how we process and transmit data. The US recently launched the National Quantum Initiative (NQI) to foster collaboration across multiple government agencies in order to strengthen US leadership in QIS and support the next generation of quantum scientists and engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic Fabrication</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/atomistic-fabrication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/atomistic-fabrication/</guid>
      <description>The scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) group utilized unique systems capable of measuring devices at cryogenic temperatures and in high magnetic fields, and performing ultra-precise lithography. Experimental research activities focus on exploring the surfaces of superconductors, magnetic thin films, and performing hydrogen lithography to synthesize devices at the atomic scale.
Research Lead: Bob Butera</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryologic Labs</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/cryologic-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/cryologic-labs/</guid>
      <description>Reversible Logic Macroscopic-quantum phenomena with flux-quanta are explored to lower the energy usage of digital gates in computers. Present-day logic gates use irreversible functions, but physics allows for fundamentally more-efficient reversible gates. Free-dynamical reversible gates are possible using systems of undamped Josephson junctions with complex resonances. Ongoing theoretical and experimental studies of these resonances may lead to dissipationless changes in flux-quanta polarity for the future of computing.
Research Lead: Kevin Osborn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/epitaxial-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/epitaxial-materials/</guid>
      <description>The epitaxial materials group synthesizes advanced materials using molecular beam epitaxy. Experimental activities revolve around creating materials that advance the capabilities of qubit devices. Two examples are custom low-loss superconductors and semiconductor quantum well heterostructures.
Research Lead: Chris Richardson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Qubit Behavior</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/fundamentals-of-qubit-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/fundamentals-of-qubit-behavior/</guid>
      <description>Can we design qubits with longer coherence times? Is it possible for a time-independent Hamiltonian to prevent noise from decohering a quantum computation? Are there fundamental physical limits to quantumness? These are some of the research questions studied by our group.
Research Lead: Ari Mizel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Circuits With Two-Level Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-circuits-with-two-level-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-circuits-with-two-level-systems/</guid>
      <description>Custom superconducting resonators and qubits are studied to better understand coherence, noise, quantum-material properties, et cetera for the future quantum processors. Many studies are performed on atomically sized two-level systems (TLSs), a major source of decoherence. For example, TLS-energy tuning and TLS-sourced microwave lasing are implemented.
Research Lead: Kevin Osborn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Information and Device Theory</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-information-and-device-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-information-and-device-theory/</guid>
      <description>We propose new types of qubits and quantum devices for practical application from quantum computing to sensing and for advancing fundamental physics. Collaborating with experimental groups around the world we seek to understand and advance the state of the art in qubit science.
Research Lead: Charles Tahan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Information Theory</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-information-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-information-theory/</guid>
      <description>We study a number of topics including developing resource reduction methods for quantum error correcting codes; quantum algorithms for problems in group theory and combinatorics, and quantum simulation algorithms for non-linear classical systems; and quantum control protocols for the preparation of high-fidelity logical quantum states.
Research Lead: Frank Gaitan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Superconducting Devices</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-superconducting-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/quantum-superconducting-devices/</guid>
      <description>The quantum superconducting devices group measures at very low temperatures (T ~ 20 mK) a variety of quantum phenomena in circuit QED transmon devices. Our work is broadly focused on understanding 1) the physics of quantum coherent phenomena in these devices and their potential application for quantum computation and 2) the sources of noise that couple to our devices and developing mitigation strategies in an effort to improve the device’s coherence time and control fidelities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Quantum Devices and 2D Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/silicon-quantum-devices-and-2d-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/silicon-quantum-devices-and-2d-materials/</guid>
      <description>Our primary focus is the development of novel materials and technologies for quantum computer research. Motivated by our previous theoretical work on silicon quantum computer architectures, we are exploring novel approaches to creating semiconductor devices at the atomic scale: we have fabricated and measured the first silicon field effect transistor (FET) devices in which mobile electrons are confined adjacent to a hydrogen terminated silicon surface. These devices have record mobility and exhibit the sixfold valley degeneracy expected on silicon [111].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super|Semi Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/super-semi-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/labs/super-semi-lab/</guid>
      <description>The Super|Semi Lab is a new multi-PI laboratory focused on superconducting and semiconductor devices and hybrid devices like super-semi junctions and epitaxial junctions.
Research Leads: Open Positions, Charles Tahan, Chris Richardson, Ben Palmer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A publication title, such as title of a paper</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/results/publications/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/results/publications/example/</guid>
      <description>Further details on your publication can be written here using Markdown for formatting. This text will be displayed on the Publication Detail page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/2020-august-gov-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/2020-august-gov-positions/</guid>
      <description>Please apply here or inquire about open positions at the LPS Qubit Collaboratory.
Responsibilities NSA is home to one of the largest and most established in-house research organizations within the U.S. Intelligence Community (IC), employing scientists with world-class skills in fields such as mathematics, physics, computer science, engineering, and cybersecurity. We collaborate with leading industries, universities, and national laboratories to advance core competencies, leverage work in overlapping disciplines, and solve some of the most challenging national security problems thought to be intractable by adversaries and commercial industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/lqc-workforce-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/lqc-workforce-programs/</guid>
      <description>Building a &amp;ldquo;quantum-smart&amp;rdquo; workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the LPS Qubit Collaboratory</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/about/about-the-lps-qubit-collaboratory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/about/about-the-lps-qubit-collaboratory/</guid>
      <description>Quantum Information Science emerges from the intersection of quantum mechanics and information science and promises new forms of computing, sensing, and networks.
In the Fall of 2018, Agencies and offices across the federal government, including LPS, came together to write a National Strategic Overview for Quantum Information Science. Shortly thereafter, the National Quantum Initiative Act legislated new QIS Research Centers, a quantum industry consortium, and new coordinating bodies (see quantum.gov). The National Defense Authorization Acts of 2019 and 2020 called for a Department of Defense Quantum Information Science Program in support of the national effort, including designation of DOD QIS Research Centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact the LQC</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/about/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/about/contact-us/</guid>
      <description>8050 Greenmead Drive, College Park, MD 20740
Phone: (301) 935-6400 Fax: (301) 935-6723
Email us at lqc@lps.gov
Inquire about open positions at the LPS Qubit Collaboratory. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPS Solid-State and Quantum Physics Programs</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/about/lps-solid-state-and-quantum-physics-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/about/lps-solid-state-and-quantum-physics-programs/</guid>
      <description>Since 1993, LPS has funded the quantum computing research community in the United States and around the world. Find out more here.
Sponsored Research LPS, in partnership with ARO, funds (via Broad Agency Announcments and other mechanisms) a broad array of quantum computing and related research. This research program has changed substanially over the decades and presently includes these major programs:
 HiPS (High Performance Superconducting Qubit Systems) QiS (Qubits in Silicon Program) SHiFT (Stable High Fidelity Trapped Ion Systems) QCISS (Quantum Characterization of Intermediate-Scale Systems) NEQST (New &amp;amp; Emerging Qubit Science &amp;amp; Technology) CQTS (Cross-Quantum Technology Systems)  Intramural Research Beginning in 2000, LPS began active internal research in quantum information science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LQC Open Positions</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/lqc-open-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/lqc-open-positions/</guid>
      <description>The Laboratory for Physical Sciences, located at the University of Maryland-College Park, is a unique organization where university, industry, and federal government scientists collaborate on research in advanced computer, sensing, and networking technologies. Working at LPS can take the form of government, UMD, and industry positions at multiple skill levels. See below for current opportunities.
Inquire about open positions at the LPS Qubit Collaboratory. LPS Lead Researcher Positions (Government) Detailed job descriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partner With Us</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/engage/partnership-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/engage/partnership-funding/</guid>
      <description>The LQC offers a mechanism for collaborative research between LPS and academia, industry, FFRDCs, and Government Laboratories to advance foundational and transformative research on challenging problems that have hindered progress in quantum information processing and associated technologies.
We have funding to establish new partnerships along along six research thrusts, described below. These thrusts are a priority and considered ripe for one of the collaborative research avenues described in this section. Other related topic areas of similar scope may also be considered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People and Partners</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/lqc-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/people/lqc-people/</guid>
      <description>Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) Research Leads  Bob Butera, PhD Frank Gaitan, PhD Bruce Kane, PhD Ari Mizel, PhD Kevin Osborn, PhD Ben Palmer, PhD Chris Richardson, PhD, Deputy Director Charles Tahan, PhD, Director  Researchers  Coming soon  Graduate Students  Coming soon  Staff  Kim Pinckney-Lewis, PhD, Outreach Lead   LQC Visitors Faculty  Hugh Churchill, PhD, University of Arkansas, Summer 2021 Tom Wong, PhD, Creighton University, Summer 2021 - Present More coming soon  Students  More coming soon   Partners LPS was founded on the campus of the University of Maryland in 1957.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/results/lqc-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/results/lqc-publications/</guid>
      <description>2021 Publications   Y. Kim, C. J. K. Richardson, E. Waks, and J.-H. Kim, “Temporal shaping of single photons by engineering exciton dynamics in a single quantum dot,” APL Photonics 6, 080801 (2021).
  D. Aiello, D. D. Awschalom, H. Bernien, T. Brower-Thomas, K. R. Brown, T. A. Brun, J. R. Caram, E. Chitambar, R. Di Felice, M. F. J. Fox, S. Haas, A. W. Holleitner, E. R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of Quantum Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/events/summer-of-quantum-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/events/summer-of-quantum-workshop/</guid>
      <description>2022 Overview Stay tuned!
2021 Overview A recap of the 2021 workshop is available here.
The Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) Qubit Collaboratory (LQC) is hosting a Summer of Quantum Workshop for rising undergraduate seniors and graduate students enrolled in physics and engineering programs. Leading quantum scientists will provide a two-week introduction to quantum computing from algorithms to physical implementations. The workshop will include quantum tutorials, interactive, hands-on projects, and virtual lab tours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Gaps in Postsecondary Quantum Education and Training</title>
      <link>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/events/workshop-on-gaps-in-postsecondary-quantum-education-and-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.qubitcollaboratory.org/events/workshop-on-gaps-in-postsecondary-quantum-education-and-training/</guid>
      <description>The Laboratory for Physical Sciences (LPS) Qubit Collaboratory (LQC) is hosting a workshop on gaps in postsecondary quantum education and training. At this free, online workshop, speakers from academia, government, and the private sector will share what is being done to develop the quantum workforce at the undergraduate, graduate, and career levels. We will identify gaps and needs in educational and training activities in order to move toward a larger, broader, and more inclusive quantum workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
